Guide to the Auxiliary of the Center for Hearing and Speech Records
University of Houston Libraries
Auxiliary of the Center for Hearing and Speech Records
1977-2015
02/2015-002
The Auxiliary of the Center for Hearing and Speech
2.00 linear feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
This collection contains materials related to the establishment of the Auxiliary fundraising board of the Houston Center for Hearing and Speech, formerly known as the Houston School for Deaf Children. Press clippings, school newsletters, copies of speeches, and gala and meeting invitations are all included.
Historical Note:
The Center for Hearing and Speech (formerly known as the Houston School for Deaf Children) was established in 1947 by the parents of deaf children. The school focuses on teaching hearing impaired and deaf children to lip-read and use residual hearing to communicate orally with hearing individuals. This collection focuses on the Auxiliary of the Center for Hearing and Speech, which was founded in 1969 to raise funds for the school, which has a sliding tuition scale.
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
Auxiliary of the Center for Hearing and Speech; The Center for Hearing and Speech
Genre/Form of Material:
Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence; Scrapbooks; Speeches (documents); Yearbooks
Topical Term:
Deaf -- Education -- United States -- Texas -- Houston; Deaf -- Means of Communication; Deafness in children
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research
Related Materials:
Betty C. Jukes Papers
Information about related materials is available at http://archon.lib.uh.edu/index.php?p=collections/controlcard&id=551&q=jukes
Scope and Contents
This collection contains materials related to the establishment of the Auxiliary fundraising board of the Houston Center for Hearing and Speech, formerly known as the Houston School for Deaf Children. Press clippings, school newsletters, copies of speeches, and gala and meeting invitations are all included.
Detailed List of Contents
- Yearbooks, id165327
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains the student and staff yearbooks for the Houston Center for Hearing and Speech, formerly known as the Houston School for Deaf Children.
  - Houston School for Deaf Children Yearbook, 1982; id165330 (Box 1, Item 1)
  - Houston School for Deaf Children Yearbook, 1983; id165331 (Box 1, Item 2)
  - Houston School for Deaf Children Yearbook, 1984; id165332 (Box 1, Item 3)
  - Houston School for Deaf Children Yearbook, 1985; id165333 (Box 1, Item 4)
  - Houston School for Deaf Children Yearbook, 1989; id165334 (Box 1, Item 5)
- Publicity, Photos, Scrapbooks, and other materials, id165328
  This series contains publicity clippings, scrapbooks, correspondence, newsletters, and speeches related to the Auxiliary of the Houston Center for Hearing and Speech.
  - HSDC Gala Scrapbook Sheets, 1995; id165336 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Gala Planning Tea Photos, 1980; id165337 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Press Clippings, 1981-2015; id165338 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Invitations, 1977-2006; id165339 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Newsletters, 1977-2014; id165340 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Speeches, 1977-2014; id165341 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1979-2010; id165342 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - The Auxiliary of the Houston School for Deaf Children Scrapbook, 1970-1985; id165344 (Ovsbox 2, Item 1)
  - The Auxiliary of the Houston School for Deaf Children Scrapbook, 1986-1995; id165345 (Ovsbox 2, Item 2)
  - The Developmental Approach to Sucessful Listening II, 1992; id165346 (Ovsbox 2, Item 3)